foreign
welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this video I am going to show you how
you can work with test case design
classes
first let's understand what is a test
case design class and why should we use
it now test case design class in Tosca
helps us to minimize redundancy in our
test sheets
so we can create a test case design
class for attributes which are
repeatedly being used in different test
sheets so by having a common class which
has got the common attributes you can
just use the references of this class in
different test sheets so that you don't
need to create this attribute a number
of different times or multiple times
and then you can also centrally manage
uh if there are any changes to this
attributes or instances
let's look at an example and try to
understand this in a better way
so I have opened this vehicle insurance
application and as you can see there are
different types of vehicles here
automobile truck motorcycle camper right
but what you will notice is if you look
at the automobile section you will see
there is enter vehicle data
and then there are some Fields here
right now if I go to truck you will see
the same section enter vehicle data and
there are some common fields in both of
these sections there are some additional
Fields here like the payload and total
weight but apart from that remaining
things are all same right now similarly
for motorcycle and for camper also you
have got some similar Fields right and
as we know these fields could be
converted into attributes and instances
in our test case design sheet right so
that's how we design our test cases
now if I go into Tosca and I've created
these two different sheets you can see
for one for automobile and one for truck
right now here you will see that I have
created these different attributes for
enter vehicle data okay so these are all
the fields which are present and then it
has got its respective instances right
each attribute has got its own instances
similarly I have created another sheet
called truck and I have created another
attribute with all the different
attributes and instances
again we are duplicating uh the
attributes in both the sheets and also
the instances right so as you can see
there is a case here to make it
redundant to not repeat or use the same
attribute multiple times we can reduce
our efforts and time in creating this
attributes and instances or even later
on uh maintaining them if there are any
changes we can create a common class
which can contain all these common
attributes okay and then we can
centrally manage them in that particular
class
now coming to how we can create a
particular class
so we can do it multiple ways one way is
to go to a folder which is your test
case design folder right click on that
and you will find an option to create a
class so I can click on this and it will
create a class here right now inside
this class I can add the attributes and
instances so whatever I require or
whatever is needed for different test
sheets so these are all the common
attributes which we have entered here
right
so this is uh the manual way of creating
the class
the other way around is you can create a
class from a module also
okay so how you can do that is let's
delete this class and now
um I will take this module called enter
vehicle data
and I'm going to drag it into this
particular folder
and now you will see that it has created
a class on its own called enter vehicle
data and it has got all the different
attributes and instances
obviously I need to make some changes
here uh all the instances may not be
correct here right but my main aim of
creating a class is to have these common
attributes inside this particular class
I can add or remove any particular
attribute I can change the instances
values here okay but then this is the
central place where I will managing all
these common attributes and now instead
of creating attributes manually or
adding them manually to my sheets
multiple times what I can do is I can
use the class reference
so now if I remove this and I just go
ahead and select the sheet I can now
drag this class into my sheet
okay and then also for the next one I
can do the same
now here you will see that uh this
automobile test sheet is using a class
reference okay
and same for truck it is also using a
class reference
okay so it is just a reference to that
particular class
also if I make any changes here like if
I delete this particular instance okay
the same will be reflected here so now
you can centrally manage your changes
across the attributes which are commonly
used in different sheets okay so if you
are using a particular class reference
whatever changes you make in the class
will be reflected in the class reference
now for example in the truck section
okay I need to add some more attributes
and I don't want to use this class
reference
so what you can do is you can resolve
the class reference so right click on
the class reference and there is an
option to resolve class reference and
now it will convert it into a simple
attribute like it was previously and
then I can go ahead and I can add my own
attributes here right so like for
example in the truck section we have
payload and total weight
so
I am going here and I'm going to create
payload
and total weight
now once you resolve the class reference
there is no link between the class and
this particular attribute so now it is
not centrally managed for this
particular attribute okay but this
reference is still there now if you want
to jump to the reference class you can
right click and click on jump to refresh
class okay
so this way you can reduce your
redundancy across your test sheets by
keeping your common attributes inside a
class and then using that class
reference across different sheets
now it completely depends on how you
want to design your classes whether you
do it from the modules or you can do it
by creating a class manually and then
adding all the attributes which you
think could be used multiple times
across different sheets
okay so this was a simple example where
you can use the class and there could be
several places where you could use
classes so just like test case libraries
which increases the reusability factor
classes also helps you to basically
reuse something what you have already
created
you can use it multiple times across
different test sheets
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video